 let questions = {
  /* ---------------------------HTML Questions------------------------- */
  Html: [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: " The correct sequence of HTML tags for starting a webpage is -",
    answer: "HTML, Head, Title, Body",
    options: [
      "Head, Title, HTML, body",
      "HTML, Body, Title, Head",
      "Head, HTML, Title, Body",
      "HTML, Head, Title, Body"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " Which of the following element is responsible for making the text bold in HTML?",
    answer: "b",
    options: [
      "pre",
      "a",
      "b",
      "br"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following tag is used for inserting the largest heading in HTML?",
    answer: "h1",
    options: [
      "h4",
      "h2",
      "h1",
      "h6"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "How to create an unordered list (a list with the list items in bullets) in HTML?",
    answer: "ul",
    options: [
      "ol",
      "ul",
      "li",
      "i"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following tag is used to insert a line-break in HTML?",
    answer: "br",
    options: [
      "a",
      "pre",
      "br",
      "b"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Where is the meta tag only found?",
    answer: "The home page",
    options: [
      "The last page",
      "The home page",
      "The second page",
      "The third page"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What should values always be enclosed in?",
    answer: "Quotation marks",
    options: [
      "Quotation marks",
      "Commas",
      "Parenthesis",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },



   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The <hr> tag in HTML is used for",
    answer: "horizontal ruler",
    options: [
      "new line",
      "vertical ruler",
      "new paragraph",
      "horizontal ruler"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following tag is used to make the underlined text?",
    answer: "u",
    options: [
      "i",
      "ul",
      "u",
      "pre"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following HTML tag is the special formatting tag?",
    answer: "pre",
    options: [
      "p",
      "pre",
      "b",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------CSS Questions------------------------- */
Css:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The property in CSS used to change the background color of an element is - ",
    answer: "background-color",
    options: [
      "bgcolor",
      "color",
      "background-color",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The HTML attribute used to define the inline styles is - ",
    answer: "style",
    options: [
      "style",
      "styles",
      "class",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following CSS property is used to set the background image of an element?",
    answer: "background-image",
    options: [
      "background-attachment",
      "background-image",
      "background-color",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct syntax to make the background-color of all paragraph elements to yellow?",
    answer: "p {background-color : yellow;}",
    options: [
      "p {background-color : yellow;}",
      "p {background-color : #yellow;}",
      "all {background-color : yellow;}",
      "all p {background-color : #yellow;}"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following property is used as the shorthand property of margin properties?",
    answer: "margin",
    options: [
      "margin-right",
      "margin-left",
      "margin",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The CSS property used to specify the transparency of an element is -",
    answer: "opacity",
    options: [
      "filter",
      "opacity",
      "visibility",
      "overlay"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is used to specify the subscript of text using CSS?",
    answer: "vertical-align: sub",
    options: [
      "vertical-align: sub",
      "vertical-align: super",
      "vertical-align: subscript",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The CSS property used to specify whether the text is written in the horizontal or vertical direction?",
    answer: "writing-mode",
    options: [
      "writing-mode",
      "text-indent",
      "word-break",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following syntax is correct in CSS to make each word of a sentence start with a capital letter?",
    answer: "text-transform: capitalize;",
    options: [
      "text-style: capital;",
      "transform: capitalize;",
      "text-transform: capital;",
      "text-transform: capitalize;"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The CSS property used to make the rounded borders, or rounded corners around an element is -",
    answer: "border-radius",
    options: [
      "border-collapse",
      "border-radius",
      "border-spacing",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------JavaScript Questions------------------------- */
Javascript:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which type of JavaScript language is _",
    answer: "Object-based",
    options: [
      "Object-Oriented",
      "Object-based",
      "Assembly-language",
      "High-level"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " Which one of the following also known as Conditional Expression:",
    answer: "immediate if",
    options: [
      "Alternative to if-else",
      "Switch statement",
      "If-then-else statement",
      "immediate if"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In JavaScript, what is a block of statement?",
    answer: "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
    options: [
      "Conditional block",
      "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
      "both conditional block and a single statement",
      "block that contains a single statement"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The 'function' and 'var' are known as:",
    answer: "Declaration statement",
    options: [
      "Keywords",
      "Data Types",
      "Declaration statements",
      "Prototypes"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",
    answer: "The local element",
    options: [
      "Global Variable",
      "The local element",
      "The two of the above",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which one of the following is the correct way for calling the JavaScript code?",
    answer: "Function/Method",
    options: [
      "Preprocessor",
      "RMI",
      "Function/Method",
      "Triggering Event"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "In the JavaScript, which one of the following is not considered as an error:",
    answer: "Division by zero",
    options: [
      "Syntax error",
      "Missing of semicolons",
      "Division by zero",
      "Missing of Bracket"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Choose the correct snippet from the following to check if the variable 'a' is not equal the 'NULL':",
    answer: "if(a!==null)",
    options: [
      "if(a!=null)",
      "if(a!null)",
      "if(a!==null)",
      "if(a!)"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In JavaScript, what will be used for calling the function definition expression:",
    answer: "Function literal",
    options: [
      "Function prototype",
      "Function literal",
      "Function calling",
      "Function declaration"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which one of the following operator is used to check weather a specific property exists or not:",
    answer: "in",
    options: [
      "Exists",
      "exist",
      "within",
      "in"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Node.js Questions------------------------- */
Nodejs:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following statement is correct?",
    answer: "js is Server Side Language",
    options: [
      "js is Server Side Language",
      "js is the Client Side Language",
      "js is both Server Side and Client Side Language",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " What does the REPL stand for?",
    answer: "REPL stands for Read Eval Print Loop.",
    options: [
      "REPL stands for Read Earn Point Learn.",
      "REPL stands for Research Eval Program Learn.",
      "REPL stands for Read Eval Print Loop.",
      "REPL stands for Read Eval Point Loop."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In which language is Node.js written?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "JavaScript",
      "C",
      "C++",
      "CoffeeScript",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following command is used to install the Node.js express module?",
    answer: "$ npm install express",
    options: [
      "$ npm install express",
      "$ node install express",
      "$ install express",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",
    answer: "The local element",
    options: [
      "Global Variable",
      "The local element",
      "The two of the above",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following extension is used to save the Node.js files?",
    answer: ".js",
    options: [
      ".java",
      ".node",
      ".js",
      ".txt"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The Node.js modules can be exposed using:",
    answer: "exports",
    options: [
      "module",
      "exports",
      "expose",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following module is not a built-in node module?",
    answer: "fsread",
    options: [
      "zlib",
      "https",
      "dgram",
      "fsread"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In JavaScript, what will be used for calling the function definition expression:",
    answer: "Function literal",
    options: [
      "Function prototype",
      "Function literal",
      "Function calling",
      "Function declaration"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is the default scope in the Node.js application?",
    answer: "Local",
    options: [
      "Local to object",
      "Global Function",
      "Local",
      "Global"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Express.js Questions------------------------- */
 Expressjs:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following are the core features of the Express framework?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "It allows us to set up middleware to respond to HTTP Requests.",
      "It defines a routing table that can work as per HTTP Method and URL.",
      "It is used to render the HTML pages dynamically.",
      "All of the above."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " What is the way to store local variables that can be accessed within the application?",
    answer: "Using app.locals",
    options: [
      "Using Config file",
      "Using database",
      "Using app.locals",
      "Using app.storage"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Where are the captured values populated regarding the route parameters?",
    answer: "req.params",
    options: [
      "req.data",
      "app.locals",
      "req.params",
      "All of the above"
      
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: " How is it possible to create chainable route handlers for a route path in Express.js?",
    answer: "Using app.route()",
    options: [
      "Using app.route()",
      "Using app.routes()",
      "Using app.router()",
      "Using app.routing()"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: " Which of the following function arguments are available to Express.js Route handlers?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "req - the request object",
      "res - the response object",
      "next",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: " In Express.js, the method app.all(path, callback [, callback ...]) can accept all HTTP methods:",
    answer: "True",
    options: [
      "True",
      "False",
      "Insufficient data",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: " Which of the following is the correct statement in the context of Express.js",
    answer: "Express is a minimal and flexible Node.js web application framework.",
    options: [
      "Express is a minimal and flexible Node.js web application framework.",
      "Express is a minimal and flexible React.js web application framework.",
      "Express is a minimal and flexible Redux.js web application framework.",
      "Express is a minimal and flexible Angular.js web application framework."
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following is the Scaffolding in Express.js?",
    answer: "Both A & B",
    options: [
      "Yeoman",
      "Express application generator",
      "Handler functions",
      "Both A & B"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is a middleware in Express.js?",
    answer: "function(req,res,next){ }",
    options: [
      "function(req){ }",
      "method(req){ }",
      "function(req,res,next){ }",
      "method(req,res,next){ }"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct syntax to use Express.js in Node?",
    answer: "var app = require('express')();",
    options: [
      "var = require('express')();",
      "var_require('express')();",
      "var app = require('express')();",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
 ],
// /* ---------------------------Angular.js Questions------------------------- */
 Angularjs:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following statement is correct for AngularJS?",
    answer: "AngularJS is a JavaScript framework",
    options: [
      "AngularJS is an HTML framework",
      "AngularJS is a Java framework",
      "AngularJS is a JavaScript framework",
      "AngularJS is a SQL framework"

    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " On which of the Architectural pattern AngularJS is based?",
    answer: "MVVM Architectural pattern",
    options: [
      "Observer Pattern",
      "Decorator pattern",
      "MVVM Architectural pattern",
      "MVC Architecture pattern"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct syntax for writing AngularJS expressions?",
    answer: "{{expression}}",
    options: [
      "{{expression}}",
      "[expression]",
      "(expression)",
      "{{{expression}}}"
      
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: " Which of the following directive is used to bind the application data to the HTML view in AngularJS?",
    answer: "ng-bind directive",
    options: [
      "ng-model directive",
      "ng-app directive",
      "ng-bind directive",
      "ng-init directive"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: " Which of the following syntax is correct for applying multiple filters in AngularJS?",
    answer: "",
    options: [
      "{{ expression | {filter1} | {filter2} | ... }}",
      "{{ {filter1} | {filter2} | ...-expression}}",
      "{{ expression - {filter1} - {filter2} - ... }}",
      "{{ expression | filter1 | filter2 | ... }}"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following statement is true about the lowercase filter? ",
    answer: "The lowercase filter converts a text to lower case text.",
    options: [
      "The lowercase filter converts a text to lower case text.",
      "The lowercase filter is a function that takes text as input.",
      "Both of the above",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is an advantage of AngularJS? ",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "AngularJS provides reusable components.",
      "AngularJS code is unit testable.",
      "AngularJS uses dependency injection and makes use of separation of concerns.",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following is used to share data between controller and view in AngularJS?",
    answer: "using services",
    options: [
      "using factory",
      "using Model",
      "using $scope",
      "using services"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What is the use of Angular Controllers in the application?",
    answer: "Angular controllers are used for controlling the data.",
    options: [
      "Angular controllers are used for displaying the data",
      "Angular controllers are used for controlling the data.",
      "Both of the above",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following is not a valid AngularJS filter?",
    answer: "email",
    options: [
      "email",
      "orderby",
      "currency",
      "lowercase"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------React.js Questions------------------------- */
Reactjs:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct name of React.js?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "React",
      "React.js",
      "ReactJS",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which of the following are the advantages of React.js?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "React.js can increase the application's performance with Virtual DOM.",
      "React.js is easy to integrate with other frameworks such as Angular, BackboneJS since it is only a view library.",
      "React.js can render both on client and server side.",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is not a disadvantage of React.js?",
    answer: "The JSX in React.js makes code easy to read and write.",
    options: [
      "React.js has only a view layer. We have put your code for Ajax requests, events and so on.",
      "The library of React.js is pretty large.",
      "The JSX in React.js makes code easy to read and write.",
      "The learning curve can be steep in React.js."
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following command is used to install create-react-app?",
    answer: "npm install -g create-react-app",
    options: [
      "npm install -g create-react-app",
      "npm install create-react-app",
      "npm install -f create-react-app",
      "install -g create-react-app"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "What of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?",
    answer: "Virtual DOM",
    options: [
      "Original DOM",
      "Virtual DOM",
      "Both A and B.",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "A class is a type of function, but instead of using the keyword function to initiate it, which keyword do we use?",
    answer: "Class",
    options: [
      "Constructor",
      "Class",
      "Object",
      "DataObject"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following acts as the input of a class-based component?",
    answer: "Props",
    options: [
      "Class",
      "Factory",
      "Render",
      "Props"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following keyword is used to create a class inheritance?",
    answer: "Extends",
    options: [
      "Create",
      "Inherits",
      "Extends",
      "This"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What is the default port where webpack-server runs?",
    answer: "8080",
    options: [
      "3000",
      "8080",
      "3030",
      "6060"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "How many numbers of elements a valid react component can return?",
    answer: "1",
    options: [
      "1",
      "2",
      "4",
      "5"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Django Questions------------------------- */
 Django:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is a Django App?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Django app is an extended package with base package is Django",
      "Django app is a python package with its own components.",
      "Both 1 & 2 Option",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Django was introduced by",
    answer: "Adrian Holovaty",
    options: [
      "Adrian Holovaty",
      "Bill Gates",
      "Rasmus Lerdorf",
      "Tim Berners-Lee"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "which of these is not a valid backend for caching in django?",
    answer: "django.core.cache.backends.sys.memory",
    options: [
      "django.core.cache.backends.sys.memory",
      "django.core.cache.backends.db.DatabaseCache",
      "django.core.cache.backends.locmem.LocMemCache",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What are Migrations in Django?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "They are files saved in migrations directory.",
      "They are created when you run makemigrations command.",
      "Migrations are files where Django stores changes to your models.",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which architectural pattern does django follow?",
    answer: "MVT",
    options: [
      "PHP",
      "MVT",
      "HTML",
      "None of the Above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Django is based on which framework?",
    answer: "MVT",
    options: [
      "MVC",
      "MVT",
      "MVVM",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What does {{ name }} this mean in Django Templates?",
    answer: "The name will be replaced with values of Python variable.",
    options: [
      "{{ name }} will be the output.",
      "It will be displayed as name in HTML.",
      "The name will be replaced with values of Python variable.",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of these variables are the settings for django contib staticfiles app?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "STATIC_URL",
      "STATIC_ROOT",
      "STATICFILES_DIRS",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is a valid forloop attributes of Django Template System?",
    answer: "forloop.counter0",
    options: [
      "forloop.reverse",
      "forloop.firstitem",
      "forloop.counter0",
      "forloop.lastitem"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: " Which of the following is the Django shortcut method to more easily render an html response?",
    answer: " render_to_response",
    options: [
      "render",
      "response_render",
      "render_to_response",
      "render_to_html"
    ]
  },
 ],
// /* ---------------------------MySQl Questions------------------------- */
 Mysql:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "To use MySQL on your computer, you’ll need",
    answer: "Some sort of client program to access the databases",
    options: [
      "Perl, PHP or Java",
      "Some sort of client program to access the databases",
      "A Browser",
      "FTP and Telnet"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "MySQL comes with as standard with client libraries for: ",
    answer: "C only",
    options: [
      "C only",
      "Java only",
      "Java and C",
      "Perl, PHP and C"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following can add a row to a table? ",
    answer: "Insert",
    options: [
      "Alter",
      "Add",
      "Insert",
      "Create"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The USE command",
    answer: "Should be used to choose the database you want to use once you’ve connected to MySQL",
    options: [
      "Is a pseudonym for the SELECT command",
      "Has been deprecated and should be avoided for security reasons",
      "Should be used to choose the database you want to use once you’ve connected to MySQL",
      "Is used to load code from another file"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "MySQL runs on which operating systems?",
    answer: "Unix and Linux only",
    options: [
      "Unix and Linux only",
      "Linux and Mac OS-X only",
      "Unix, Linux, Windows and others",
      "Any operating system at all"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT supported by MySQL ",
    answer: "Stored Procedures",
    options: [
      "Temporary (Hash) Tables",
      "Table Joining",
      "Stored Procedures",
      "Regular Expression Matching"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of these is a valid call to a function (watch the spaces carefully!)",
    answer: "CONCAT( “A” , “B” )",
    options: [
      "CONCAT( A , B )",
      "CONCAT ( A , B )",
      "CONCAT( “A” , “B” )",
      "CONCAT ( “A” , “B” )"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "If you want to undo a GRANT, you should use",
    answer: "REVOKE",
    options: [
      "REVOKE",
      "UNDO",
      "UNGRANT",
      "WITHDRAW"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is available in MySQL:",
    answer: "CREATE DATABASE",
    options: [
      "CREATE VIEW",
      "CREATE SCHEMA",
      "CREATE TRIGGER",
      "CREATE DATABASE"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "How many distinct, different values can you hold in an enum field? ",
    answer: "65535",
    options: [
      "255",
      "7",
      "65535",
      "635"
    ]
  },
 ],
/* ---------------------------php Questions------------------------- */
Php:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "PHP stands for - ",
    answer: "Hypertext Preprocessor",
    options: [
      "Hypertext Preprocessor",
      "Pretext Hypertext Preprocessor",
      "Personal Home Processor",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Variable name in PHP starts with - ",
    answer: "$ (Dollar)",
    options: [
      "! (Exclamation)",
      "$ (Dollar)",
      "& (Ampersand)",
      "# (Hash)"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which of the following is the default file extension of PHP?",
    answer: ".php",
    options: [
      ".php",
      ".hphp",
      ".xml",
      ".html"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following is not a variable scope in PHP?",
    answer: "Extern",
    options: [
      "Global",
      "Static",
      "Local",
      "Extern"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following is used to display the output in PHP?",
    answer: "Both echo and print",
    options: [
      "echo",
      "write",
      "print",
      "Both echo and print"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following is the use of strlen() function in PHP?",
    answer: "The strlen() function returns the length of string",
    options: [
      "The strlen() function returns the type of string",
      "The strlen() function returns the length of string",
      "The strlen() function returns the value of string",
      "The strlen() function returns both value and type of string"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is used for concatenation in PHP?",
    answer: ". (dot)",
    options: [
      "+ (plus)",
      "* (Asterisk)",
      ". (dot)",
      "append()"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following is the use of strpos() function in PHP?",
    answer: "The strpos() function is used to search for a character/text in a string",
    options: [
      "The strpos() function is used to search for the spaces in a string",
      "The strpos() function is used to search for a number in a string",
      "The strpos() function is used to search for a character/text in a string",
      "The strpos() function is used to search for a capitalize character in a string"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct way to create a function in PHP?",
    answer: "function myFunction()",
    options: [
      "Create myFunction()",
      "New_function myFunction()",
      "function myFunction()",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following is the correct use of the strcmp() function in PHP?",
    answer: "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings including case",
    options: [
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings excluding case",
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the uppercase strings",
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the lowercase strings",
      "The strcmp() function is used to compare the strings including case"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Mongodb Questions------------------------- */
Mongodb:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "MongoDB is written in _",
    answer: "All",
    options: [
      "Go",
      "JavaScript",
      "Python",
      "All"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "A collection and a document in MongoDB is equivalent to ___ concepts respectively.",
    answer: "ITable and Row",
    options: [
      "Table and Column",
      "Table and Row",
      "Column and Row",
      "Database and Table"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "in how much time the MongDB writes are written to the journal?",
    answer: "100 ms",
    options: [
      "100 s",
      "60 s",
      "1 s",
      "100 ms"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "In which format MongoDB represents document structure?",
    answer: "BSON",
    options: [
      "BSON",
      ".txt",
      ".Docx",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "A collection in MongoDB is a group of",
    answer: "Related documents",
    options: [
      "Databases",
      "Schema",
      "Rows",
      "Related documents"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "which field is always the first field in the document.?",
    answer: "_id",
    options: [
      "_id",
      "Ob_id",
      "id",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "mongoDB supports",
    answer: "NoSQL",
    options: [
      "RDBMS",
      "NoSQl",
      "Both",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "MongoDB is a ..... type database?",
    answer: "document",
    options: [
      "Relational",
      "objects",
      "document",
      "All"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which statements is correct about mongoose in MongoDB ?",
    answer: "It is used for modeling your application data in node.js",
    options: [
      "It is Java library to connect with MongoDB",
      "It is used for modeling your application data in node.js",
      "It is Python library to connect with MongoDB",
      "It is a PHP library to connect with MongoDB"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The concatenation of the collection name and database name is called a -",
    answer: "Namespace",
    options: [
      "Namespace",
      "MongoDB",
      "sharding",
      "replica"
    ]
  },
],
/* ---------------------------Springboot Questions------------------------- */
Springboot:[
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which among these is not an applications server provided by Spring Boot?",
    answer: "Binary link",
    options: [
      "Jetty",
      "Embedded Tomcat",
      "Binary link",
      "Undertow"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: " Which one of following is an alternative to Spring HibernateTemplate",
    answer: "Hibernate contextual sessions",
    options: [
      "Hibernate contextual sessions",
      "HibernateContext",
      "Both of the above",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What is bean in Spring?",
    answer: "An object",
    options: [
      "A component",
      "An object",
      "A class",
      "A container"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "What is the scope of bean in portlet context?",
    answer: "global-session",
    options: [
      "session",
      "request",
      "prototype",
      "global-session"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which method is used to process bean before initialization callback",
    answer: "postProcessBeforeInitialization()",
    options: [
      "scope",
      "postProcessAfterInitialization()",
      "postProcessBeforeInitialization()",
      "it's own constructor"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which tag is also allowed by static field?",
    answer: "util:constant",
    options: [
      "util:constant",
      "list",
      "constructor-args",
      "set"
    ]
  },

   {
    numb: 7,
    question: "How many types of method injection are available in spring?",
    answer: "2",
    options: [
      "4",
      "2",
      "8",
      "1"
    ]
  },

  
   {
    numb: 8,
    question: "In Spring Method that allows you to start a new transaction is called -",
    answer: "getTransaction()",
    options: [
      "getTransaction()",
      "commit()",
      "rollback()",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Annotation which decorates the PostageServiceBean is",
    answer: "@Interceptors",
    options: [
      "@Mention",
      "@Autowire",
      "@Wire",
      "@Interceptors"
    ]
  },


   {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which are the ioc container in spring?",
    answer: "Both ApplicationContext and BeanFactory",
    options: [
      "ApplicationContext",
      "BeanFactory",
      "Both ApplicationContext and BeanFactory",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
],


};